this exercise asks us to
write a method that counts down to zero
using recursion so let's call our method
count two zero
and we're going to pass in an argument
which is going to be the number that we
want to count down from
so we'll call this perimeter number
and let's first just think about
counting down from 10. so when we
invoke this method we want it to count
down from 10 to 0
and output each number
so in order to output the number we
would invoke put us
now if we run our code we just expect to
output 10.
and that's what we see
so in order to recursively count down to
zero
we want to call this method
and as an argument we'll pass in one
less than the current number
now when this method call on line three
is executed
number will be one less so we would
count down from 10
to nine to eight and this will output
the number
let's run our code and you can see that
we raised an error stack level too deep
we need to think about what type of stop
condition we're going to provide this
recursive method
well we know that we want to stop
counting down when we've reached zero
so let's use an if statement
and we'll provided the condition if
number
is less than or equal to zero
we're going to output the number
otherwise we want to output the number
and invoke count to 0 again
so we'll continue outputting number and
invoking count to 0
with number being one less than the
current number
up until number is less than or equal to
zero
at that point we'll just output the
number and return from the method
let's run our code now and we expect to
output 10
down to zero
and that's what we see
let's run our code one more time let's
count from 20 to zero
and we see the expected output
[Music]
now lastly you may have wondered on line
2 why we needed to check whether number
was
less than or equal to zero and we wanted
to do that in case a negative number
were passed
as the argument to count to zero
if a negative number is passed to the
method then we simply want to output the
number and return from the method
let's run this code to make sure that's
the behavior we see
and it is
you